M/P

PROFILE

Passionate and hard-working full stack systems developer with experience in system development for university level projects. I am extremely skilled in programming as I have been a private programming tutor (C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, MVC, ASP.NET) for students in many different universities from beginner to advanced concepts during my 3 years of study in Bcom Informatics (Information Systems) at the University of Pretoria.

CONTACT

PHONE: 076 767 4103

FMAII.

Manesanpillay28@gmail.com

SHORT COURSES

The King's School Linbro Park

First-Aid and CPR training, 10 Hours community service Learn-to-learn study skills Leadership development course

University of Pretoria

40 Hours community service, EBIT WEEK

HOBBIES

Forex/Index/Stock trading

MANESAN PILLAY

Full stack system developer

EDUCATION

University of Pretoria, South Africa (UP)

January 2017 - Present

I started at UP with the BIT degree however the course work taught was not the pathway in contemplated forging. I had then transferred over to the BCom Informatics degree and absolutely enjoyed full stack development as well as following and practicing the entire life cycle of system development. This degree has contributed to majority of my system development and programming knowledge and has shaped me into an excellent full stack developer.

The King's School Libro Park, South Africa

April 2011 - November 2016

- IEB Matric Certificate
- I achieved a bachelor's pass at the end my school career

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Pretoria [Final year, full system development project for Black Gold Properties, South Africa]

February 2020 - Present

- I am the lead programmer and system designer for our team project that Black Gold Properties, South Africa will take on and fully implement in their business practices
- I came up with quick, viable solutions to the many problems we faced throughout the system development phases
- I worked well with the project development team and we constantly remained in top 5 for our deliverables of the system throughout 2020 as we were constantly ranked against other teams

LanLink [Part-time system developer vacation job]

June 2018 - July 2018

- This was my first introduction into real-life system development and how systems are built in a framework as well as the deployment and hosting process
- I learned a lot about system development and the potential of pursuing this career path under the guidance and advice of the CEO as well as employees of LanLink

PROGRAMMING/SYSTEM DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- C#
- ASP.NET Web API
- Angular 2+
- ASP.NET
- ASP.NET MVC
- Linq querying
- Typescript
- JavaScript
- HTML & CSS
- SASS
- SQL Server 2014
- SQL database design
- Ionic Framework
- Electron Framework
- Razor
- Bootstrap
- WordPress
- Microsoft Office
- Google Drive
- OneDrive

LEADERSHIP/PEOPLE SKILLS

- Lead coder and system designer for 2 project development teams
- Great problem solver finding viable options
- Quick thinker
- Logical/analytical
- Good teamwork skills
- Project management and project life cycle planning skills

REFERENCES

Available upon request